If you look through the media player documentation, you'll find this method,
عند الاطلاع على مستندات توثيق مشغل الوسائط، ستعثر على هذه الطريقة،
setOnCompletionListener.
setOnCompletionListener.
So the description says here that this method
الوصف هنا يقول أن هذه الوظيفة
allows you to register a callback.
تسمح لك بتسجيل أي استدعاء.
They'll be called when the end of the media source or
سيتم استدعاؤها عند نهاية مصدر الوسائط
audio file has been reached.
أو عند الوصول إلى الملف الصوتي.
Notices that the input of this method is an on completion listener.
ولاحظ أن إدخال هذه الوظيفة هو OnCompletionListener.
So let's click into it for more details.
ولذا، هيا بنا ننقر فوقها لمزيد من التفاصيل.
So MediaPlayer.OnCompletionListener is an interface.
ومن ثم فإن OnCompletionListener لمشغل الوسائط تمثل واجهة.
So that means you'll need to implement it and
وهذا يعني أنك بحاجة إلى تنفيذها
provide the code for it's onCompletion() method.
وتوفير الكود لوظيفة onCompletion.
So the answer to this first question is that the onCompletion() method
وبالتالي فإن الإجابة على السؤال الأول هو وظيفة onCompletion
of the onCompletionListener object will be called
وسيتم استدعاء كائن onCompletionListener
when the MediaPlayer has finished playing the media file.
عند انتهاء مشغل الوسائط من تشغيل ملف الوسائط.
And then in step number two, I asked you to use this information.
وبعد ذلك، في الخطوة رقم 2، سأطلب منك استخدام هذه المعلومات.
To modify the music player sample app.
لتعديل التطبيق العينة لمشغل الموسيقى.
So that when the song is done playing, a toast message pops up.
ومن ثم، عند تشغيل الأغنية، ستظهر رسالة منبثقة.
So let's go back to our music player project in Android Studio.
ولذا هيا بنا نعود إلى مشروع مشغل الموسيقى في آندرويد ستوديو.
So after the media player started,
وبعد بدء تشغيل مشغل الوسائط،
I'm going to set up a callback to be notified when the song is done.
سأقوم بإعداد استدعاء ليتم إخطارنا عند الانتهاء من تشغيل الأغنية.
And as noted in the quiz hint we provided you, we need to set up
وكما لاحظت في نصائح الاختبار التي قدمناها لك، نحن بحاجة إلى
the completion listener after the media player has started.
إعداد OnCompletionListener قبل بدء تشغيل مشغل الوسائط.
So after mediaPlayer.start is called,
ولذا بعد استدعاء بدء تشغيل مشغل الوسائط،
let's call the set on completion listener method.
هيا بنا نستدعي المجموعة الموجودة في وظيفة OnCompletionListener.
So inside this method I'm going to define an anonymous listener class
ومن ثم داخل هذه الوظيفة سأحدد فئة مستمع مجهولة
in line and remember that it's anonymous because I'm not giving it a class name.
في السطر وتذكر أنه مجهول لأنني لم أعطيه اسم فئة.
So there's no need to give it a class name here.
ولذا ليس هناك حاجة إلى تسمية الفئة هنا.
Because I'm only going to be using this class definition once.
لأنني سأستخدم تعريف الفئة مرة واحدة.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now inside the onCompletion method I'm going to modify it so
والآن داخل وظيفة onCompletion سأقوم بالتعديل
that it pops up a toast message that says, I'm done!
كي تظهر رسالة منبثقة تقول، انتيهت!
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
All right, so now let's test it, I'm going to hit the play button.
حسنًا، هيا نختبرها الآن، سأضغط على زر التشغيل.
[MUSIC]
[MUSIC]
And when it's done, the toast message pops up.
وعند الانتهاء، تظهر الرسالة المنبثقة.
So great work.
عمل عظيم.
So to summarize, I'm using an asynchronous callback
لتلخيص ما مضى، أنا أستخدم استدعاء المزامنة
to get notified when the media player is done playing the song.
لإشعاري عند انتهاء مشغل الوسائط من تشغيل الأغنية.
And in the meantime, I can go about doing other things.
وفي ذلك الأثناء، سأقوم بفعل بعض الأشياء الأخرى.
Like respond to other button clicks from the user.
مثل الرد على زر آخر نقر فوقه المستخدم.
All while waiting to get called back.
وذلك في انتظار الحصول على الاستدعاء.